When I started out doing software development, I was mostly just making little
在我刚开始做软件开发的时候 我基本上只做些让自己开心的小项目
projects that amused me, little apps, little command-line tools, and stuff like that.
像小应用程序 命令行小工具之类的
I just really didn't know that it was so easy to contribute
我只是真的不知道作出贡献那么容易
and that you don't need to have solved P=NP,
而且你不需要解决 P = NP 那样的难题
your input can still be valuable.
你的投入依然可以是很有价值的
Local communities made me confident enough to contribute.
本地社区使我有了足够的信心去做出贡献
When I was a total newbie to programming, I teamed up with my friend Dan
当我还完全是个编程新手的时候 我和我的朋友 Dan 一起
to make my very first open source pull request (PR)
发起了我的第一个开源拉取请求（PR）
which would also make it my very first open source contribution
这也是我的第一次开源贡献
I'd heard so much about contributing to open source, about how amazing it was,
我听过很多为开源做贡献的故事 说它有多么神奇
but also how completely terrifying. I was very aware,
又有多么可怕 我很清楚
not all communities are kind and not all maintainers are nice.
并非所有社区都和善 也不是所有维护者都很友好
The project itself was a pretty good one for a first timer.
那个项目本身对新手来说相当不错
We were just adding a JavaScript library,
我们只是添加了一个 JavaScript 库
something to let people get a digital walkthrough of the website.
让人们可以在线预览网站
Just a nice well–scoped project. Self–contained.
这是一个很好的适用范围很广 自成体系的项目
Bonus, if the thing didn't work,
而且如果这玩意儿不起作用
I was almost positive it wouldn't burn down the whole site.
我基本上确信它不会毁掉整个网站
Yet, I was crazy nervous about this pull request.
然而 我对这个 PR 非常紧张
Dan and I read the docs for the library,
我和 Dan 阅读了这个库的文档
plugged away at our code.
埋头于写我们的代码
I still remember when we were finally done, we just looked at each other
我仍记得当我们最终完成的时候 只是互相看着彼此
like, "That's it?"
好像在说：“就这样吗？”
We made our PR, it was reviewed, got merged,
我们发起了 PR 它被审查 然后合并
and I guess I was surprised by how,
我想我至今还是对这一切感到惊讶
I don't know, how mechanical it all was.
这一切 都这么机械化么？
It wasn't some big mystery or magical thing that only they could do.
这并不是什么只有他们才能做到的 也不是什么神秘或神奇的事情
I realized, I really could contribute, too.
我意识到我确实也可以对开源作出贡献
That's a bit of knowledge we're passing on in this episode;
这是我们在这一集中想要传递的一点知识
making a contribution to open source isn't magic.
为开源做出贡献并不神奇
It doesn't have to be terrifying.
它也不一定可怕
We're going to walk through this together.
我们将带你一起走过这个过程
It was just such a groundbreaking realization
这是一个突破性的认识
that this is actually totally open, I can just do this.
这些项目实际上是完全开放的 我也可以做出贡献
In that opener, you heard from command line heroes,
在这一场的开场白中 你会听到像你一样的代码英雄
just like you, who push through that same terror to join the ranks of open source.
在加入开源行列时 经历着同样的恐惧
They were Nolan Lawson, Lindsey Tulloch, and Kanika Muraka,
他们分别是 Nolan Lawson、 Lindsey Tulloch、 Kanika Muraka
all heroes.
这些是今天来做客的代码英雄
You're listening to Command Line Heroes, an original podcast from Red Hat.
你正在收听的是红帽公司的原创播客节目《代码英雄》
I'm your host, Saron Yitbarek.
我是主持人 Saron Yitbarek
This is a story about two command line heroes
这是一个关于两个代码英雄的故事
just trying to make something better in the big open source world.
他们只是想在广阔的开源世界中 做出更好的东西
One of them is a contributor, the other's a maintainer.
他们其中一个人是贡献者 另一个人是维护者
Neither of them are real people,
他们都不是真实存在的人物
instead these two fictional characters
而是两个虚构人物
represent all the contributors and all the maintainers that shared their stories with us.
用来代表所有的贡献者和维护者 他们和我们分享了他们的故事
Hopefully, you'll see some of yourself in their journey, too.
希望你也可以在他们的历程中看到一些你自己的影子
First meet our friend, the contributor.
首先来见一见我们的朋友 - 贡献者
She's a bit of a newbie, just like we all were once upon a time.
她是个新手 就像曾经的我们那样
She's not sure about what the basic workflow is, but she sees a need
她不确定基本的工作流是什么 但是她看到了一个需求
and she thinks she can add a feature that would help.
并且认为她可以添加一个功能来提供帮助
Our imaginary contributor is keen to make that fix, but how?
我们这个虚构的贡献者很想提交代码 但是该怎么做呢
You're always growing new skills and you don't have to have
你一直在成长 学习新技能 而且你不一定
taken apart a computer as a child to know how to code as an adult.
需要在孩提时代拆过电脑 才有资格在成年后学写代码
That's Corinne Warnshuis,
这位是 Corinne Warnshuis
the executive director of an awesome organization called Girl Develop It.
一个名叫“Girl Develop It” 的很棒的组织的执行董事
It's designed to help women who maybe don't feel super comfortable
该组织的目的是帮助那些可能不太敢提问的
asking questions or might not feel entirely welcome at meetups.
或在聚会中觉得自己不太受欢迎的女性
Girl Develop It realized that making contributions isn't the same for everybody;
Girl Develop It 意识到做出贡献的难度并不是对所有人而言都是一样的
culture matters. Part of our job as a community
这是社会造成的问题 作为社区 我们的一部分职责
is to build a little empathy and healthy diversity into the process.
就是要让世界多一点同情心 以及包容健康多元文化
There are many barriers to entry as we see them,
在我们看来 加入开源的壁垒有很多
but we like to call them "no good reasons."
但我们喜欢称它们为“没有充分的理由”
There are three no good reasons that keep women specifically out of technology.
有三个这样的壁垒将女性专门排斥在技术之外
They are: stereotypes, they're the accessibility, and the environment.
它们是：刻板印象、可及性和环境
It's worth remembering here promoting diversity doesn't just make good ethical sense,
值得记住的是 促进多元化不仅具有良好的道德意义
it makes good business sense, too.
同时也有商业意义
Technology as an industry has probably the greatest potential
作为一个行业 技术可能拥有着
to make the most change in the world today.
最大的潜力 能给当今世界带来最大的变化
You really want to have people from all backgrounds, from all perspectives
你确确实实希望 来自各行各业的人们都为
contributing to the tools and services and things that are going to shape the world.
塑造世界的工具 服务和其他事物做出贡献
I think it's really important that people from all backgrounds are creating software and
我认为来自各种背景的人们一起开发软件
contributing to open source projects.
并为开源项目做出贡献真的非常重要
The fact is, we didn't all start with the same advantages or experiences.
事实是 我们并非一开始就拥有同样的优势和经验
The next great coder might not look like a Silicon Valley cliché.
下一代的伟大开发者可能看上去并不像硅谷的程序员
In–person instruction has been historically incredibly expensive and inaccessible for people.
面对面指导对人们而言 历来是非常昂贵而又难以获取的
Again, I think from 2014 to today, that has improved.
再者 我认为从 2014 年至今 情况有所改善
I think groups other than Girl Develop It like
我认为除了 Girl Develop It 之外的组织
Outreachy, like CodeNewbie,
（比如 Outreachy 和 CodeNewbie ）
are doing that by providing
正通过提供安全的网络或空间
a safety net or a space to ask questions and get more comfortable.
来提出问题并获得更多的舒适感来做到这一点
Having a safe, welcoming testing ground for some of those ideas and some of those questions
为这些想法和问题提供一个安全而友好的测试平台
is a good place to start.
是一个不错的起点
Speaking of newbies, back to that contributor we were tracking.
说到新手 回到我们正在追踪的那个贡献者
When you're not from a mainstream background,
倘若你不是来自主流背景时
that first commit can carry a lot of weight.
那么第一次提交可能会压力非常大
It can feel like you have to prove yourself.
感觉就好像你必须得证明你自己
Once we get those barriers to entry low enough,
不过一旦我们将加入的壁垒降得足够低
what do we actually need to think about as we prepare to contribute?
我们在准备做出贡献时 实际需要考虑的是什么呢
It's cool to get excited about certain projects,
对某些项目感到兴奋这事很酷
but what is the use case that you're trying to solve?
但你想要解决的用例是什么呢
Vincent Batts works at Red Hat, mostly on container architecture.
Vincent Batts 在红帽主要从事容器架构方面的工作
He encourages new contributors to try and be intentional about the work.
他鼓励新的贡献者尝试并有针对性地开展工作
Find that niche where you and the project make sense together.
找到对你和项目都有意义的利益基础
I think a project to contribute to usually comes out of
我认为一个可让人持续贡献的项目
a reciprocal relationship.
通常来自于互惠关系
It satisfied a need for you, and along the way you found a way
它满足了你的一个需求 而且在这个过程中你又发现了
to satisfy a need for it, and it becomes a relationship,
满足它的需求的方式 即使它是一个由人构成的社区
even if it is a community of people.
它也已经成为了一种共生体系
For example:
比方说：
I ended up standing up a Slackware Linux box out of a recommendation by a friend.
因为朋友的推荐 我最终弄了一台 Slackware Linux 机器
It was suitable enough for me to do what I was trying to do that I ended up helping them
它非常适合我想做的事情 最后我帮着
get it packaged for the mainstream Slackware Linux community.
将其打包到了主流 Slackware Linux 社区
And ended up becoming a maintainer and contributor on that project,
并最终成为了这个项目的贡献者和维护者
not because I sought out to be a contributor to that Slackware Linux community,
这并不是因为我想成为 Slackware Linux 社区的贡献者
but it most well suited
而是因为这是最适合我的一个项目
the other project, the use case that I was actually trying to solve.
它的用例正好是我一直致力于解决的事情
I think that happens a lot for a lot of folks. They seek to write a database because
我想很多人都会遇到这种情况 他们因自己量身定制的用例
of their tailored use case, and they find that it works well in Golang,
而编写一个数据库软件 他们发现用 Golang 编写很合适
and they wrote such a high–performance database that they were able to contribute back
因此他们写了这样一个高性能的数据库 所以他们能够
fixes or improvements to Golang to help their database run faster.
对 Golang 做出修复或优化方面的贡献 以帮助他们的数据库运行得更快
ou can find your little niche and let a certain amount of organic growth take place.
你可以找到你自己的小众领域 并开始自然发展
The key point is, start somewhere.
关键在于 从某处开始去做
You don't have to wait for a degree or for absolute confidence.
你不必等待有了学位或绝对的自信才开始
If you need direct experience
如果你需要直接
writing code or writing docs, or even
编写代码或文档的经历
being a system administrator for a back-end database web server
或是成为一个后端数据库、Web 服务器的系统管理员
most of these communities are volunteer based.
那么好消息是 大部分社区都是由志愿者构成的
You go out to some project like Debian, Fedora, or whatever,
你可以参与诸如 Debian、Fedora 或其他一些类似的项目
and those communities have docs pages that are set up.
这些社区都建立起了文档页面
Those have to run on a web server somewhere and somebody,
那些项目必须在某处的 Web 服务器上运行
even a community member that's not being paid
一些人 甚至是一个没有薪酬的社区成员
to check if the web server's down or something went wrong, is gaining experience.
负责去检查 Web 服务器是否停机或出了什么问题 这也算是积累经验
Vincent stresses that point about the egalitarian nature of open source.
Vincent 强调了开源的平等主义本质
Wherever you're coming from, you really can start contributing, if you want to.
无论你来自哪里 只要你愿意 都可以真正开始做出贡献
You can make a name for yourself, if that's what you want to do.
如果你想的话 你可以为自己扬名立万
Once it's merged, then your name is attached to something.
一旦它被合并 你的名字就会附在某个项目上
You're publicly representable that you have made
你可以公开表示你在某个地方做出了改进
an improvement somewhere,
which is incredibly meaningful.
这是相当有意义的事情
I've worked with folks that were television repairmen and teachers,
我曾与那些不是从事日常技术工作的
not in a technical day–to–day job, that were
电视修理工和教师共事过
very well represented. They contributed a lot in the community.
他们很有代表性 他们也在社区上做出了很多贡献
On the flip side of that, I've worked with developers that
另一方面 我也曾和一些开发者合作过
sometimes have had 30 years of development experience, but they had never
他们有的能有 30 年开发经验
publicly contributed code like that.
但他们从来没有像那样公开贡献过代码
How's our contributor doing by the way? Well, she found her niche.
对了 我们的贡献者怎么样了？嗯 她找到了她的定位
She conquered her fears and she's finally made her first pull request.
她克服了她的恐惧 并最终发起了她的第一个 PR
Now she can sit back
现在她可以休息一下
and be terrified while she waits for the maintainer to respond.
并战战兢兢地等待维护者作出回复
Contributing upstream is kind of like going on stage for the talent show for the first time;
向上游做贡献有点像第一次上台做才艺表演
you get nervous, and you go out there and your palms get sweaty. You do a thing
你会感到紧张 走上舞台后手心冒汗 你做了一件事
and then it's like an achievement. You are
然后它好像就变成了你的成就
profoundly changed, you never will be the same.
你将被彻底改变 跟过去不再一样
Profoundly changed? Maybe.
彻底改变？或许吧
There are in fact four possible responses from a maintainer;
事实上 维护者有四种可能的回应：
silence, that's a fun one,
沉默 - 这很“有趣”
or possibly outright rejection,
也可能是完全拒绝
or outright acceptance.
或是直接接受
Or the squishy middle ground,
或是柔和的中间立场
a request for change.
要求修改
A couple days after her PR,
提交 PR 的几天后
our imaginary contributor finally gets a ping back from the maintainer.
我们虚构的贡献者终于收到了来自维护者的回复
Lo and behold, it's a request for change.
跪迎结果吧 是要求修改
Being new, she takes that as a miniature disaster.
作为一个新手 她将这视为一场小型灾难
She doesn't know yet how request for change is really an accomplishment.
她还不知道要求修改是个实际上是成功的一步
She even gets a flash of anger at the clipped tone the maintainer is using.
她甚至还对维护者的简略语气感到一点气愤
It sort of sounds like he doesn't have time for her. There's a wall up,
听上去就像维护者没空搭理她一样 这里存在着一堵墙
and that new contributor has got no idea what's happening on the other side.
新的贡献者不知道墙的另一边正在发生什么
Meet a maintainer.
我们来认识一位维护者
The project he's maintaining isn't his full time job;
他正在维护的项目并不是他的全职工作
it's a weekend project and he stays up till the wee hours lots of nights
这是一个周末项目 他时常熬到深夜
prioritizing issues, and reminding folks to update docs when they make pull requests,
给工单排优先级 并且提醒人们发起 PR 时更新文档
and you get the idea. He's got a full plate.
然后你就明白了 他相当忙碌
Sometimes he even experiences a little maintenance burnout.
有时甚至出现了一些维护倦怠
A real life maintainer, Nolan Lawson,
一位现实生活中的维护者 Nolan Lawson
wrote a pretty amazing post that got a lot of traction recently about burnout.
写了一篇很棒的有关倦怠的文章 最近引起了很多关注
I think part of that blog post was kind of a cry for help, honestly.
老实说 我认为那篇博文有一部分实在寻求帮助
It was me expressing that I had stumbled into this open source thing.
这是我表达我自己偶然发现了这个开源的项目
It was really fun at first, and now it wasn't so fun. I wasn't sure
起初我觉得它确实很有趣 但现在却感觉没那么有趣了
what I should do to recover.
我不确定该如何恢复兴致
Nolan's got a day job, but like most maintainers
Nolan 有一份日常工作 但和大多数维护者一样
he was putting in tons of after hours work on his open source project
他在开源项目中投入了大量的休息时间
because the guy honestly cares. Ironically,
因为这家伙真的很在意这个项目 讽刺的是
part of his pain was coming from the fact that he knows the contributors honestly care, too.
他的部分痛苦来自于 他清楚贡献者也同样很在意这个项目
What really burned me out more than anything was actually just the flood of well–meaning folks.
真正使我精疲力竭的实际上只是如潮水般涌来的好心人
You want to help them; you really, really do.
你真的想帮他们 真的真的很想
All they're doing is asking a question,
他们所做的只是问一个问题
all they're doing is - they found a legitimate bug in your project that's blocking them,
他们所做的就是 - 他们在你项目中发现了阻碍他们的 bug
or all they're doing is - they
或者他们所做的只是
actually bothered to download the code and figure out how it builds and to contribute
他们真的费心去下载代码并弄清楚它是如何构建的
a bug fix. They just want you to review their code that they've contributed.
并提供 bug 修复 他们只是希望你审查他们贡献的代码
Maintainers like Nolan are constantly reviewing a library of PRs,
像 Nolan 这样的维护者正不断地审查 PR 库
figuring out how commits will play into things.
弄清每个提交将如何发挥作用
They're pushing contributors to do the best work possible,
他们促使贡献者尽可能做到最好
to conform to the house constraints,
遵守内部限制
to contribute in ways that are most meaningful to the larger goals of the project.
为了能让项目达到更高的水准 用最有意义的方式做出贡献
Here is my point, chances are
我的观点是 有可能
those maintainers are not the jerks a new contributor might worry about.
和新贡献者想得不同 维护人员可能并非混蛋
They're working their butts off trying to get to everything.
他们正努力地想去做到一切
They even take the time, lots of maintainers do,
他们甚至会花时间（很多维护者都这样）
to label some things as reserved for first–timers only
标注一些东西保留给新手
so newbies have a chance to take a swing. At the end of the day though,
以便新手有机会施展自己 但到最后
the scope of all the PRs and commits gets overwhelming.
PR 和提交总是非常的多
How do we make sure that doesn't happen?
我们要如何确保这种情况不会发生呢
How do we create environments for maintainers that make sense?
我们该如何为维护者创造合理的环境呢
One solution is an open source project with a strong community like Fedora.
一种解决方案是 - 拥有像 Fedora 项目一样强大的社区
The Fedora project leader Matthew Miller
Fedora 项目负责人 Mattew Miller
explains what attracts maintainers and contributors to the project.
解释了项目吸引维护者和贡献者的地方
A lot of Fedora is not development,
Fedora 项目中许多不光是开发
it's all the things that go around development.
还有开发过程中所相关的一切
That's actually true with IT in general, CS (computer science) in general. Open source
总体来说 IT、 CS（计算机科学）事实上都是如此
maybe doesn't have enough of it, the sort of support roles around open source.
开源可能并没有足够的这类支持性的角色
What does that support actually look like?
这种支持实际上看起来是怎样的呢
One of the paid roles we have for example is the Fedora program manager
我们拿来举例的带薪职位之一是 Fedora 项目经理
who helps keep the schedule on track,
他帮着让计划按部就班进行
and bugs people about making sure the paperwork is done.
并且监管着人们来保证文书工作完成
Having somebody paid to do it
让人有酬劳地来做这份工作
actually helps keep the bureaucracy down because they can put
事实上可以帮着减少官僚主义 因为他们可以
the time in to make it a human thing
把时间花在使项目成为人看懂的事情
rather than something that is just a bunch of paper shuffling.
而不只是一堆杂乱的文件
I think having corporate involvement like that gives
我认为 像这样的企业
stability to some of the roles
参与某些角色
that you can't guarantee with volunteers.
可以赋予你无法用志愿者保证的稳定性
It sort of reminds me of those work spaces freelancers use
这有点让我想起了自由职业者使用的共享工作空间
There's a shared reception area, shared wifi, and shared coffee.
那里有一个共享的接待区 共享的 WiFi 和共享的咖啡
The manager's handling it, and you're free to do your own thing.
有一个人在管理它 然后你就可以自由地做你自己的事情
Matthew told us about another Fedora fix.
Matthew 告诉了我们 Fedora 采取的另一种策略
They save you from feeling like everything will collapse
他们让你想在项目中途停下来休息一下时
if you take a break from your project.
可以很自然 而不是感觉一切都崩溃了
One of the things we've looked at is making natural endings to leadership roles,
我们研究的一个问题是确保领袖角色的漂亮退场
where you say you sign up for something, it's not necessarily a lifetime commitment.
所谓的职位并不一定是终身的委任
You can re–sign up,
你可以重新申请担任角色
you're not kicked out after a year.
并且不会在一年任期后结束后 看起来像被踢出去似的
If after six months you want to move on,
如果六个月后你想离开
you can gracefully go on without feeling like you're letting people down.
你可以优雅地这样做 而不必觉得这会让人失望
We've tried to work on making sure people have a clear exit.
我们已在努力确保人们可以没有障碍地退出
Matthew figures that finding ways to support that open source community
Matthew 认为 找到支持该开源社区的方法
without being heavy–handed is the key.
而又不至于重蹈覆辙才是关键
It's almost like a family rather than something like a workplace or something like that.
社区几乎就像一个家庭 而不是工作场所之类的东西
It's meaningful to contribute to
在这里做出贡献很有意义
because you're working on this not just for yourself, or not just for some
因为你不仅只在为自己或是某些
paycheck or an end product, but because the people you're working on it with are your friends and
薪酬或终端产品工作 而且由于共事的是你的朋友
t's something that you're working on together to make something that's bigger than this individual effort.
你们一起工作能做出比单人作品更伟大的东西
Whether it's thanks to Fedora or something else,
无论是 Fedora 还是其他社区
a world where open source contributions are sustainable,
它们都造就了一个开源贡献得以持续的世界
now that's a world worth fighting for.
这个世界还值得努力让它继续变好
Meanwhile, back at her desk,
同时 让我们回到办公桌旁
that new contributor we were following just finished the changes the maintainer asked for.
我们关注的那个贡献者刚完成了维护者要求的修改
She doesn't realize it yet, but she's about to have her first pull request accepted.
她还没意识到 但她即将拥有第一个被接受的 PR
It's easy to lose sight of those early steps
当我们谈论诸如倦怠之类的长期工作的问题时
when we talk about long–term issues like burnout.
很容易忽视那些早期问题
Every day, there are new contributors all over the world joining the party.
每天都有很多新的贡献者加入进来
That's really why we need to build a sustainable humane place
这实际上就是为什么我们需要构建可持续的社区
where all this open source magic can happen.
为所有这些开源魔术提供场地
In the end, our contributor and our maintainer work together to nudge things forward.
最终 我们的贡献者和维护者共同努力 推动事情向前发展
There's one last piece of the story—
故事的最后一句话是
remember that all that back and forthing depends on development platforms
记住所有的交流都依赖于
like GitHub and GitLab,
GitHub 和 GitLab 之类的开发平台
places where we can all come together.
这些平台使得我们可以聚集到一起
I wanted to dive deep into how those communities make our work possible.
我想深入探讨一下这些社区是如何使我们的工作成为可能的
I got chatting with Shannon Crabill about it.
我和 Shannon Crabill 谈过这个问题
Shannon's an email developer by day,
Shannon 白天是个电子邮件开发者
but by night she's learning front–end development.
但到了晚上 她正在学习前端开发
She's also someone who knows first–hand about the value of community.
她也是一个对社区价值有第一手了解的人
Last year she participated in a month–long celebration of open source
去年她参加了一个长达一个月的
called Hacktoberfest,
名为 Hacktoberfest 的开源活动
an initiative to get more people to contribute to open source.
该活动旨在让更多的人为开源做出贡献
At the time, Shannon was very much an open source newbie.
当时 Shannon 完全是一个开源新手
Thinking back to that point in October,
回想起十月那时候
I felt like I wasn't finding much to work on and there's probably other beginners or maybe even more beginners
我感觉我没有太多工作要做 而且可能还有更多的新手
who were also not finding things to work on. Maybe if I put something out there that's
没找到需要做的东西 如果我提出一些
elatively easy, they'll have some place to try and learn,
相对容易的待办事项 他们就可以找到用于尝试和学习的突破口
and get used to Git and GitHub.
并且开始习惯使用 Git 和 GitHub
I think the hardest part is getting used to the motions of
我认为最困难的部分 在于习惯工作流程
just how it works and practicing. How do I push repo? How do I share a project?
并付诸实践 如何推送存储库？如何分享项目？
How do I do pull requests and that sort of thing.
如何处理 PR 和相关的东西？
I got people to contribute,
我帮助人们对开源做出了贡献
which was surprising, but also really awesome.
这事令人惊讶 感觉也确实很棒
Was that scary at all? I feel like
真的很恐怖吗？我觉得
if you're new,
如果你是个新手
you're putting yourself out there despite even having the repo, period.
尽管你拥有存储库 也要走出自己的小世界 把自己放在社区里
Now you have people actually contributing and you have to
现在 维护者所在的社区里出现了正在作出贡献的人
talk to them, and review their code, and have opinions.
你必须和他们交谈 审查他们的代码并发表意见
That sounds like that can be a little intimidating.
这听上去是有点吓人
I think the initial reactions were like,
我认为最初的反应是
"Oh my God, this is so cool",
“哦 我的天哪 这太酷了”
and also, "Holy crap, what have I gotten myself into?"
还有 “天哪 我让自己陷入了什么境地？”
I realized I had
我意识到
merged my own code into my own code,
我只合并过自己的代码
I merged my own pull requests and pushed to the
合并过自己的 PR 并将其推送到自己的站点上
site and everything like that. I had not done anyone else's. I think I hadn't done
以及其他所有只关于自己的事情 我从没处理过别人的东西
a pull request, merging it before then,
我认为我之前尚未完成过真正意味上的合并 PR
so I had to figure that out.
所以我不得不把这弄清楚
Merge complex in general
总的来说 将复杂的东西简单地合并起来
is something that I still struggle with a little bit.
仍然是我要努力熟练解决的问题
It was this whirlwind of feelings,
体验很复杂 像一阵旋风那样
"This is cool. I don't know how to go about this."
“这很酷 但我不知道该怎么做”
Everyone was really friendly, and I just tried to stay very friendly and honest,
每个人都很友好 并且我也努力保持非常友好和真诚
even if it was just, "Hey, I'm overwhelmed.
即使只是 “嘿 我有点不知所措
I see everyone's pull request. I won't get to them tonight, but I'll get to them tomorrow."
我看到了每个人提交的 PR 虽然今晚我不会找他们 但我明天会的
People seemed to respond well to that.
人们对这种情况似乎反应良好
Yes. One thing that I've always wondered when you are
是的 我一直想知道的是
maintaining a project—especially as a newer developer—is
当你维护一个项目时 尤其是作为一个新的开发者时
does it mean that you have to be the smartest person on the repo?
是不是这意味着你必须是整个存储库贡献者中最聪明的人
You're essentially grading, you're judging and reviewing other people's code.
你实际上在评估、评判并审查其他人的代码
Have you had a situation where you didn't know as much as the person making a pull request?
你是否遇到过 自己懂的东西不如提交 PR 的人那么多的情况
How did you deal with that?
你是如何处理的
That's a really good one.
好问题 我认为
I could see thinking that, "Oh, I need to be the smartest, best developer ever,"
“噢 我需要成为有史以来最聪明最好的开发者”
would maybe be a hindrance.
这样的想法会成为障碍
I think I was lucky that I didn't think that
我觉得自己很幸运 当我
when I went into this, so I was able to go into it like,
进入这个领域的时候 我没有这样想 所以我能
"Let's just go for it, see what happens."
像这样说 “让我们先开始 并且期待未来会发生什么吧”
You don't need to be senior developer, 20 years experience.
你无需成为一个有 20 年经验的高级开发人员
You just need to have an idea and just
你只需要有一个好点子
know how to use the software, and just be willing to learn if you don't know.
知道如何使用相应软件 然后愿意去学习自己不知道的东西
There were definitely one or two pull requests that added some really cool features to my project that
肯定有一两个 PR 为我的项目添加了一些很酷的功能
to be honest, if it broke, I don't really know how to fix it.
说实话 如果它们崩溃了 我真不知道该如何修复
I can look at the code and be like, "Yeah, it's broken."
我可能会看着代码然后想道 “是的 它崩溃了”
To be able to build that from scratch, I wouldn't know how.
我不知道该怎么做才能从头构建它们
I think that's the cool thing about it. If it was just
我认为这就是它酷的地方 如果只有
me contributing, I might have done some neat stuff
我一个人在做贡献 我或许也能做出些不错的成果
but not as cool as what other people are bringing
但没法像其他拥有丰富经验的人所作出的贡献一样
their experiences to the table with to do.
将项目变得那么酷
As a maintainer, what are some
作为一个维护者
lessons that you've learned along the way to make the project more
在使项目更易于访问 更加友好
accessible, more friendly, easier to contribute to?
更加易于贡献的过程中 你学到了些什么呢
Sure. The one thing that I think was really helpful,
哦 确实有件我认为很有帮助
and I wish I had done this initially,
并且我希望我一开始就做的事
is to set up templates wherever possible
那就是尽可能的建立模板
and documentation, documentation, documentation.
以及文档、文档、文档
I definitely added a lot to my README file as I went,
我的确在我的 README 文件里加了很多东西
and I think just having a README file to start is a really big step.
并且我认为在项目开始时有一个 README 文件确实是很重要的一步
Just even links to,
这件事情意味着
"Hey, check out our guidelines for contributing."
你对其他人大声说 “嘿 请查看我们的贡献指南”
I think I made a pull request template,
我认为我制作了一个 PR 模板
I made issue templates, "Click here to see current issues,"
一个议题模板 “单击这里查看当前议题”
so people aren't submitting the same things multiple times.
这样人们才不会多次提交同样的内容
Making it as easy as possible, or as user friendly as possible,
我认为让项目尽可能简单 或尽可能对用户友好
I think is a big step you can do as a maintainer.
这是你作为维护者需要迈出的一大步
Absolutely.
绝对是这样
READMEs, I see them all the time, I hear about how important they are;
我经常看到 README 文件 经常听说他们有多么多么重要
I feel like it's also
我觉得在
there's so much you can do in a README. At the end of the day,
README 文件里还可以做很多事情 归根结底
it's kind of a blank document that tells people to read it.
它就像是一个空白文档 告诉别人去阅读它
What do you do in that document? How do you structure it
你应该在文档里写什么呢 你该如何构建它
to make it really connect with people who are looking to contribute?
来使得它真正与希望做出贡献的人产生关联呢
I think in my README I had a lot gifs in there.
我在我的 README 文件里放了很多 gif
What I was starting to hear was that Shannon had quickly learned how important the relationships are.
我一开始就知道 Shannon 已经认识到了合作关系的重要性
She knew straight away that the work was going
她早就知道 如果有人被邀请来协作
to shine if people were invested,
这项目就会变得耀眼
and even having a good time.
大家也会因此度过美好的时光
...There's people doing great things with open source projects,
...有人用开源项目作出很棒的事情
I also think it can be fun and
我也认为这很有趣 而且
a fun project to say, "Hey, I made these cool bats
有个有意思的项目 “嘿 我制作了这些很酷的蝙蝠
that randomly generate on this page every time you click."
每次你单击页面的时候 它们都会随机生成
I also love that there's so many different types of things that people
我也喜欢人们做不同的事情
can do. If you're really into the artistic cool stuff,
如果你真的很喜欢艺术性的东西
you can do the bat generation feature.
你可以做蝙蝠生成功能
If you want to clean up, you can do that, too.
如果你想让项目变得整洁 你也可以做
If you're like, "I'm going to stick to the documentation, I'm going to
如果你想说 “我会坚持贡献文档 我将
spend my time to make this room, this place, a little bit cleaner
花时间为其他的贡献者们打造更干净
for all my other contributors," then there's the option to do that, too.
更舒适的环境” 那你也可以选择做这个
Yeah. I tried to make it clear that whatever you want to contribute is
是的 我已经说得很清楚了 无论你想贡献的是什么
fine with me. If you catch a spelling error and you want to fix that, great.
都没有问题 如果你发现了一个拼写错误并且想要纠正它很好
If you notice a link is broken and you want to fix that, great.
如果你发现某个链接损坏并且想要修复它 也很好
If you just want to help comment this code so it's easier to read and understand,
如果你只是想帮着注释这份代码 使得它更易于阅读和理解
that would be really helpful.
那也将很有帮助
I think it's really awesome that you had such a positive experience with the community,
我认为 你在社区中获得了积极的反馈真的很棒
because I've heard lots of stories where that really wasn't the case.
因为我听说过很多并不是这样美好的故事
People weren't very nice online, and weren't very welcoming and kind,
人们在网络上并不十分友好 也不太热情善良
especially to newbies who we tend to ask
尤其是对我们这一些 可能
some more simpler questions than are expected.
问出比他们想象中更简单问题的新手
What do you think helped make your community a
你认为 是什么使得你的社区
nicer place compared to what some other communities are like?
比起其他社区更加友好呢
Just the fact that it was a very casual thing.
只是因为在我们社区 贡献是一件很随意的事
If you want to contribute, you can, cool. If you don't, that's also cool.
如果你想做出贡献 你可以 这很酷 如果你不想 那也很酷
I definitely had the thought that open source was this big scary thing,
我理解有人认为开源是一件令人恐惧的大事
you need to have all this experience and know
你需要具备所有这些经验
all these complicated languages, or
并且了解所有这些复杂的语言
back–end and front–end and everything in between to be able to contribute to.
或是前后端以及其他的一切 才能够做出贡献
Absolutely.
确实
How has doing Hacktoberfest,
参与 Hacktoberfest
how's that changed your idea of open source now?
是怎样改变了你现在对开源的想法
It's definitely changed it for the better. Like I said, I had
它肯定对我造成了积极的影响 就像我说的
a great experience and I hope everyone that
我有过很棒的经历 而且我希望
was involved with my project in some way or another had a good experience, too.
每一个以某种方式参与我项目的人也能有很好的经历
It's definitely given me the push to want
这毫无疑问促使我想去
to try things like that more often, even if they don't go anywhere.
尝试更多类似的事情 即使它们没有进一步的发展
It seems more attainable now.
现在这看起来这些项目更加平易近人了
Music to my ears.
真是个好消息
Here's something;
这儿有个信息
thousands of people from hundreds of companies,
来自数百家公司的数千人
and some from no company at all, contribute to the Linux kernel.
以及一些根本没在公司工作的人 为 Linux 内核做出过贡献
That means Linux, which basically runs the internet,
这意味着 在互联网中不可或缺的 Linux
is maintained by a whole army of everyday heroes.
是由一群日常英雄在维护的
If you're feeling eager to make your first contribution to open source,
如果你渴望为开源作出第一次贡献
maybe you want to learn more about the Fedora community,
或许你会想了解有关 Fedora 社区的更多信息
we've got a ton of materials waiting to help you out.
我们有大量的资料正等着来帮助你
Check out redhat.com/commandlineheroes for more.
请查阅 redhat.com/commandlineheroes 以获得更多信息
Quick reminder,
快速提醒一下
this season we're building our very own open source Command Line Heroes game.
这一季我们将构建我们自己的开源《代码英雄》游戏
You are invited to contribute in whatever makes sense for you.
欢迎你以对你来说合适的方式来做出贡献
Get the deets on how to be a part of it;
快来了解如何成为其中一员吧
we would love for you to build this game with us
我们希望你可以通过 redhat.com/commandlineheroes
over at redhat.com/commandlineheroes.
和我们一起开发这款游戏
Next episode, we're all about the ruthless Darwinian process of errors
下一集 我们将讨论 错误如何经历残酷的达尔文式优胜劣汰
and the beauty of failure in open source development—
以及开源开发中失败的美丽之处
how it haunts us, guides us, and makes us better.
它如何困扰我们 指导我们 并使我们变得更好
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
《代码英雄》是红帽的原创播客
Listen for free on Apple Podcast, Google Podcast,
你可以在 Apple Podcast、 Google Podcast
or wherever you do your thing.
或是其他你喜欢的途径免费收听
I'm Saron Yitbarek, until next time, keep on coding.
我是 Saron Yitbarek 坚持编程 下期再见